Guide to The Leo Deaner Radical Left-Wing Publications collection, 1890-2017 LAC0011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets by topic, 1890-2017; Series 3
  - Publications, publishers, and presses, 1933-2017; Series 3 Subseries 2
    - Publications, publishers, presses, 1973-1978; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 68, Folder 4)
      Art and Literature: Readings from Before and After the Death of Mao Tsetung; Bourgeoisie under Socialism: Readings from Before and After the Death of Mao Tsetung; Education: Readings from Before and After the Death of Mao Tsetung; Grasp Revolution, Promote Production: Readings from Before and After the Death of Mao Tsetung
    - Publications, publishers, presses, 1974-1978; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      Australian Communist: a Journal of Marxism-Leninism-Mao Tsetung Thought, scattered issues no. 66 (1974)-no. 88 (1978)
    - Publications, publishers, presses, 1915-1936; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      Marx and Engels on Revolution in America by Heinz Neumann; Manifesto of the Communist Party by Karl Marx and Frederick Engels: Authorized English Translation, Edited and Annotated by Frederick Engels; Engels and Science by J.D Bernal
    - Publications, publishers, presses, 1971-1974; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      Rising Up Angry: a Revolutionary Organization Committee to Creating a New Man, A New Woman, and a New World, scattered issues from vol. 2, no. 11 (June 14, 1971)-vol. 6, no. 5 (September 22-October 13, 1974))
    - Publications, Publishers Presses, 1969-1974; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      Rising Up Angry: a Revolutionary Organization Committee to Creating a New Man, A New Woman, and a New World, scattered issues from vol. 1, no. 2 (August 1969)-vol. 5, no. 10 (Kamiaru 13-February 3, 1974)
    - Publications, Publishers Presses, 1978-1982; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 69, Folder 2)
      Root & Branch: a Libertarian Socialist Journal, no. 5-6 (1978), no. 10 (1982)
    - Publications, Publishers Presses, 1956-1960; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      Chinese Workers March Towards Socialism; Labour and Struggle: Glimpses of Chinese History, Supplement to China Reconstructs, April 1960
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1970-2002; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      Class Struggle: Journal of Communist Thought, no. 8 (Fall 1977); SDS/WUO: Students for a Democratic Society and the Weather Underground Organization by David Gilbert; Program and Principles of the Revolutionary Soviet Communists by the Communist Labor Party; Inner-City Voice: Official Organ of the League of Revolutionary Black Workers, vol. 2, no. 9 (November-December 1970); American Mass Line: Newspaper of the American Communist Workers Movement (Marxist-Leninist), v. 1, no. 9 (September 28, 1970)
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1968-1971; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Programme and Constitution of the Revolutionary Communist Party USA; New Programme and New Constitution of the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA; Loss in China and the Revolutionary Legacy of Mao Tsetung: Speech by Bob Avakian, Chairman of the Central Committee of the Revolutionary Communist Party USA; We Called a Strike and No One Came by Black & Red
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1966-1980; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Cuba: the Evaporation of a Myth from Anti-Imperialist Revolution to Pawn of Social-Imperialism by the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA; Guardian Debate: "… Fan the Flames' by Irwin Silber; Two Superpowers: Main Enemies of the People of the World: Interview with Michael Klonsky, Chairman of the October League; Great Strategic Concept in Defense of Chairman Mao Tsetung's Theory of the Differentiation of the Three Worlds by Workers Congress (M-L); New Programme and New Consitution fo the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA: Drafts for Discussion; Trapped in a System by Carl Oglesby; Clases y la Lucha de Clases by Revolucion: el Periodico de la Union Revolucionaria
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1961-1979; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Statement of 81 Communist and Workers Parties Meeting in Mosco USSR 1960; Building Class Struggle Trade Unions: a Communist View by The Call; No Condescending Saviors: a Study of the Experiences of Revolution in the Twentieth Century by Noel Ignatin; Study Program for Lenin's the State and Revolution by the October League M-L; Future of NAM by Ron Aronson, Steve Shank
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1972-1977; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      McGovern: a Case for Critical Support by the Radical Student Union Research Committee on McGovern; Amnesty Blues or the Private Life of an Artful Draft Avoider as told by Government Spies & Involuntary Confessions by ZIP (Code Name); Forward by Communist Workers Group (Marxist-Leninist) no. 1 (November 1976)-no. 4 (August 1977); Revolutionary Strategy in the U.S. by The New Voice; Black and White Construction Workers Divided by the Bosses reprinted from February 1970 PL, the Bimonthly Magazine of the Progressive Labor Party; Working Papers: Workplace Experiences of Members of the New American Movement; Struggle Against Revisionism and Opportunism: Against the Communist League and the Revolutionary Union by the Black Workers Congress
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1964-1978; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      Sing a Battle Song: Poems by Women in the Weather Underground Organization; Clench Fist: a History of the Communist Salute by David Emerson Gumar, reprinted from American Opinion; We Accuse: Bill Epton Speaks to the Court by CERGE (Committee to Defend Resistance to Ghetto Life); Crusader Newsletter, vol. 10, no. 2 (Summer 1969) by Robert F. Williams, Publisher in Exile; Trade Union Program by Progressive Labor Party; Draft Party Program Issued by the Marxist-Leninist Organizing Committee; Why We Strike by Marxist-Leninist Organizing Committee (MLOC); Tragedy of Vietnam: Where do We go from Here? By Helen B. Lang; All Africa is Standing Up! By Marxist-Leninist Organizing Committee
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1965-1978; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 74, Folder 2)
      Regents published by Free Speech Movement; Against Revisionism by Michael A. Miller; Free Speech Movement and the Negro Revolution by Mario Savio, Eugene Walker, Raya Dunayevskaya; SDS Education Packet; Dialectics or Dogmatism? A Further Examination of the Vanguard Party and the Mass Organization by Fred Newman
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1964-1979; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 74, Folder 3)
      Build the Leadership of the Proletariat and its Party by Revolutionary Union; American System by John Graham published by Research, Information & Publications Project, Student Union for Peace Action; Cuba vs U.S. Imperialism by Edward Boorstein; Notes on closed NMC (New Mobilization Committee) "Steering Committee" Meeting held at Mary Clark's Home I Los Angeles 10/27/69; Female Liberation as the Basis for Social Revolution—2 by Roxanne Dunbar; Provisional Platform of the Free Speech Movement; James Baldwin, Masonic Auditorium, San Francisco, December 16, Benefit for the Free Speech Movement and Its Legal Defense Fund; Berkeley Free Speech Controversy (Preliminary Report) Prepared by a Fact-Finding Committee of Graduate Political Scientists; Maoism in the U.S.: a Critical History of the Progressive Labor Party by Mary Alice Waters
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, Circa 1965-1974; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 74, Folder 4)
      Workplace Papers Printed & Distributed by Sojourner Truth Organization; Regents Receive Meyer Committee Report and Proposed University-wide Regulations Relating to Student Conduct … [et al] We Want a University: dedicated to the 800 by Free Speech Movement; How Capitalism has been Restored in the Soviet Union and What This Means for the World Struggle by Revolutionary Union; Plot Against Black America Published by the Harlem Branch of the Progressive Labor Party
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, Circa 1960-1977; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 74, Folder 5)
      Buffalo workers' Movement Working Papers, October 1977; Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on Student Conduct by Berkeley Division of the Academic Senate; Unity Statement October League (M-L); Welfare: the Big Lie Reprinted from Red Papers 3; Movement for a Democratic Military; Demonstrate Against the War in Vietnam by Peace Action Council; Selected Speeches Presented at Forums by the August 29th Movement, 1974-1975; In Search of Truth: an Analysis of the H.C.U.A Propaganda Film "Operation Abolition" by Bay Area Student Committee for the Abolition of the House Committee on Un-American Activities; Spring Mobilization Labor Committee to end the War in Vietnam; Proletarian Cause: Journal of Marxism-Leninism Mao Tsetung Thought, vol. 1, no. 1 (September 1972); Time to Speak by Liber Brunensis Publications
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, Circa 1964-1979; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 75, Folder 1)
      [Fliers, Newspaper Clippings, Letters Supporting the Committee to Defend the Conspiracy, Chicago 7]; Black workers Protest U.A.W. Racism March on Cobo Hall; Toward a Revolutionary Youth Movement by Mike Klonsky; Class Analysis of the Radical Student Movement by Fred Gordon; Vietnam Day Committee Oct. 15-16 International Days of Protest; Peace Times, vol 1, no. 1 (March 7,1970)-no. 2 (March 21, 1970) published by the Vietnam Moratorium Committee; Should the Left Support McGovern? A Discussion Paper Issued by a Marxist-Lenisist Study Group; Communist Line: a Theoretical Journal of the Marxist-Leninist Organizing Committee, No. 3 (March 5, 1976), no. 8 (April 22, 1976), no. 5 (April 30, 1976); Workers of the World Unite! Communist Party U.S.A. (Marxist-Leninist), vol. 5, no. 1 (January 15, 1979)
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1948-1980; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 75, Folder 2)
      . Love it or Leave it: an Affectionate History of the American Left by Frank Browning & Frank Viviano; How Industrial Unionism was Won: the Great Flint Strike Against General Motors 1936-1937 by Walter Linder; 200 Years is Long Enough! By the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA; Working Papers for Nyack Conference on Unemployment & Social Change distributed by Students for a Democratic Society; United States' War in Vietnam by Michael Myerson published by W.E.B. DuBois Clubs of America; Vietnam no Mistake! How the U.S, got Involved, Why the U.S. Should Get Out Now by SDS; Revolutionary Youth Movement II: Documents on SDS and the Split by Mike Klonsky, Noel Ignatin, Marilyn Katz, Sue Eanet, Les Coleman; Student Mobilizer Published by the Student Mobilization Committee, April 24, 1971; New York Notes Published by the Communist Workers Committee (Provisional of New York City)
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, Circa 1966-1977; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      On Building the Party of the U.S. Working Class and the Struggle against Dogmatism and Reformism: Speeches by Bob Avakian, Member of the Central Committee of the Revolutionary Union; Red Papers, no. [1] and no. 2, published by the Revolutionary Union; Cuba: the Evaporation of a Myth: from Anti-Imperialist Revolution to Pawn of Social-Imperialism by the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA; "Energy Crisis" and the Real Cri$i$ Behind it by David Pugh and Mitch Zimmerman; U.S.A. – the Labor Revolt by Stanley Weir, originally in International Socialist Journal; History of the New Left, 1960-1968 by James O'Brien, originally in Radical America, May-December 1968 issues; Student Movement in the '50s: a Reminiscence by Andre Schiffrin; Selective Service System or, the Manpower Channelers by Peter Henig; Politics of Ecology by Barry Weisberg, Reprinted from Liberation January 1970; Revolution and U.S. Aggression by Observer, "Known to be one of the very highest officials of the Chinese Communist Party …"; Power in American Society by Jim Jacobs, Originally published by Radical Education Project; Cuba's Revolutionary Medicine by Willis P. Butler; Two Battles from Our Past: 100 Years ago Great Strike of 1877, and 50 Years Ago Sacco & Vanzetti by The Worker; Cops are Hired to Enforce the Laws; Partners: Labor and the CIA by Sidney Lens, Reprinted from The Progressive
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1972-1980; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      On Party-Building: Against Revisionism and Dogmatism, reprinted from The Organizer, newspaper of the Philadelphia Workers' Organizing Committee; Trade Union Question: a Communist Approach to Strategy, Tactics and Program by the Philadelphia Workers Organizing Committee; Labor Study Project Report no. 1; Proletarian Revolution vs Revolutionary Adventurism: Major Documents from an Ideological Struggle in the Revolutionary Union, Red Paper no. 4 published by the Revolutionary Union; How Capitalism has been Restored in the Soviet Union and What This Means for the World Struggle, Red Paper no. 7 published by the Revolutionary Union
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1970-1971; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 75, Folder 5)
      From the Movement toward Revolution by Bruce Franklin; Radical Approach to Economics: Basis for a New Curriculum by Richard C. Edwards, Arthur MacEwan, and the Staff of Social Sciences 125
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1971-1982; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 76, Folder 1)
      Manifesto for an American Revolutionary Party; Literature & Ideology, no. 9 (1971)-no. 10 (1971) by Necessity for Change Institute of Ideological Studies, Dublin and Montreal; Selection of the Red Papers, 1,2 and 3 by the Revolutionary Union
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1971-1975; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 76, Folder 2)
      Programme and Constitution of the Revolutionary Communist Party USA; The Communist: Theoretical Journal of the Central Committee of the Revolutionary Communist Party USA
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1969-1975; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 76, Folder 3)
      Build the Anti-Imperialist Student Movement by the Revolutionary Union; Throw the Bum Out! By the Workers Committee to Throw the Bum Out; Literature & Ideology, no. 9 (Fall 1969)-no. 10 (Winter 1969) by the Necessity for Change Institute of Ideological Studies, Dublin and Montreal; Grand Illusion: the Communist Party and Trade Unionism by James Weinstein
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1971-1973; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 76, Folder 4)
      Five Articles by Chairman Mao Tsetung; Unity Statement by the October League (Marxist-Leninist); Literature & Ideology, no. 8 (1971) and no. 13 (1972) by the Necessity for Change Institute of Ideological Studies, Dublin and Montreal
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1970-1990; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 76, Folder 5)
      How to Publish a High School Underground Newspaper by Waleed S. Al-Fedhly and Gary D. Shapiro; Port Huron Statement 1962 by Students for a Democratic Society; Change Yourself to Change the World by National Organization for an American Revolution; Labor Spy's View as an Everbrite Scab; Grasping Revolutionary Theory: a Guide for Marxist-Leninist Study Groups by Irwin Silber; National Workers Organization: a Powerful Weapon for Our Class by the Revolutionary Communist Party USA; Literature & Ideology, no. 12 (1972) by the Necessity for Change Institute of Ideological Studies, Dublin and Montreal
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1979; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 77, Folder 1)
      On the Roots of Revisionism: a Political Analysis of the International Communist Movement and the CPUSA 1919-1945 by Revolutionary Road Publications
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1970-1974; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 77, Folder 2)
      Red Papers by the Revolutionary Union; Build the Leadership of the Proletariat and its Party, Red Paper no. 6, by the Revolutionary Union
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1967-1976; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 77, Folder 3)
      New Women in New China; Against U.S. Aggression for National Salvation by Ho Chi Minh; Auto and the Workers Movement: Learning from the Proud Past to Fight for a Brighter Future by the Revolutionary Communist Party USA; Uprooting Racism and Racists in the U.S.A. by National Organization for an American Revolution; To Get a Good Job, Get a Good Education by the Radical Education Project; Merger Movement: a Study in Power by Paul Sweezy and Harry Magdoff; Notes on Left Propaganda, How to Spread the Word by Leo Huberman
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      Quotations from Chairman Mao Tsetung; Road to Revolution: Communist Guerrilla Warfare in the U.S.A. by Phillip Abbott Luce
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1972-1977; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      The Communist: Theoretical Journal of the Central Committee of the Revolutionary Communist Party USA, vol. 1., no. 2 (May 1, 1977); Literature & Ideology, no. 11 (1972) by the Necessity for Change Institute of Ideological Studies, Dublin and Montreal
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, Circa 1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 77, Folder 6)
      People of the State of California versus Mario Savio and 571 Others: Appellants' Opening Brief on Appeal from the Municipal Court Berkeley-Albany Judicial District, Honorable Rupert Crittenden, Judge, Criminal no. 235, in the Appellate Department of the Superior Court County of Alameda, State of California
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1956-1962; SEries 3 Subseries 2 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder include publications from China
      Political Report of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China to the 8th National Congress of the Party Delivered on September 15, 1957 by Liu Shao-Chi; Historical Experience of the Dictatorship of the Proletariat; People's Communes in China; Thirty Years of the Communist Party of China by Hu Chiao-Mu; Wuhan in Construction; Battle for Life by Pa Chin and Others; Two Tactics, One Aim: an Exposure of the Peace Tricks of U.S. Imperialism; Comrade Mao Tse-Tung on Imperialism and all Reactionaries are Paper Tigers; Raise Higher the Banner of Mao Tse-Tung's Thought on Art and Literature by Lin Mo-Han
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1963-1967; SEries 3 Subseries 2 (Box 98, Folder 2)
      Leninism and Modern Revisionism; Truth about How the Leaders of the CPSU Have Allied Themselves with India Against China; Leaders of the CPSU are the Greatest Splitters of our Times: Comment on the Open Letter of the Central Committee of the CPSU (VII); Proletarian Revolution and Khrushchov's Revisionism: Comment on the Open Letter of the Central Committee of the CPSU (VIII); Letter of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China in Reply to the Letter of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union Dated June 15, 1964; Letter of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China in Reply to the Letter of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union Dated July 30, 1964; In support of the People of the Congo (Leopoldville) Against U.S. Aggression; Historical Experience of the War Against Fascism; Refutation of the New Leaders of the CPSU on United Action; U.S. Aggression has no Bonds and our Counter to Aggression has no Bounds; Confessions Concerning the Line of Soviet-U.S. Collaboration Pursued by the New Leaders of the CPSU; Inside Story of Tibet by Ratne Deshapriya Senanayake; May Upheaval in Hongkong Edited and Published by the Committee of Hongkong-Kowloon Chinese Compatriots of All Circles for the Struggle Against Persecution by the British Authorities in Hongkong
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1972-1977; SEries 3 Subseries 2 (Box 98, Folder 3)
      Taking Tiger Mountain by Strategy: the Story of the Modern Peking Opera; Vicious Motive, Despicable Tricks: a Criticism of M. Antonioni's Anti-china Film China by Renmin Ribao Commentator; New Page in the Annals of Sino-Japanese Relations; Highway and an Old Chinese Doctor by Rewi Alley; Glance at China's Culture by Chai Pien; Story of Chinese Acupuncture and Moxibustion by Fu Wei-kang; Chairman Mao's Theory of the Differentiation of the Three Worlds is a Major Contribution to Marxism-Leninism
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1988-1992; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 106, Folder 1)
      Contents in folder include Minority Trends Letter
      Minority Trends Letter Published by Center for Third World Organizing, vol. 1, no 3 (Summer 1988), vol. 1, no. 4 (Fall 1988), vol. 2, no. 1 (Spring 1989), vol. 3, no, 2 (Summer 1989)-vol. 3, no. 3 (Summer 1990), vol. 3, no, 4 (Fall 1990), vol. 4, no, 1 (Winter 1990/1991), vol. 4, no. 2 (Spring 1991), vol., 4, no, 3 (Summer 1991), vol., 4, no., 4 (Summer 1991), vol. 5, no, 1 (Winter 1991/1992), vol. 5, no, 2 (Spring 1992), Vol. 5, no. 3 (Summer 1992), vol. 5 no, 4 (Fall 1992)
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1952-1977; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 106, Folder 2)
      Women in China Today Published by the All-China Democratic Women's Federation; Mao Tse-Tung's Thought is the Invincible Weapon; On the Long March with Chairman Mao by Chen Chang-Feng; China Tames her Rivers; Support the Dominican People's Resistance to U.S. Armed Aggression; Commemorate the 50th Anniversary of the Communist Party of China, 1921-1971 by the Editorial Departments of Renmin Ribao (Peoples Daily), Hongqi (Red Flag), and Jiefangjun Bao (Liberation Army Daily); Drive U.S. Imperialism out of Asia! Strive to Build a Socialist University of Science and Engineering; Oppose U.S. Occupation of Taiwan and Two Chinas Plot: a Selection of Important Documents Compiled by the Chinese People's Institute of Foreign Affairs; Self-Reliance and Independent National Economic Construction by the Editorial Department of Rodong Shinmoon, Organ of the Central Committee of the Korean Workers' Party; Three Major Struggles on China's Philosophical Front (1949-64); Constitution of the People's Republic of China, 1st edition; National Question and Class Struggle by Liu Chun; Why China has no Inflation by Peng Kuang-hsi; United and Equal: the Progress of China's Minority Nationalities by Yin Ming; Secret Bulletin, Story by Kao Sha, Illustrations by Hua San-Chun; Peking Review no, 34 (August 23, 1968)
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1953-1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 114, Folder data_value_missing_e9c5488db9293ad582433ce763b53c2b)
      Contents in folder include publications by Leo Huberman
      ABC of Socialism by Leo Huberman and Sybil B. May (Monthly Review Pamphlet Series no. 7); What you Should already Know about Suez by Paul M. Sweezy and Leo Huberman (Monthly Review Pamphlet Series no. 12); Theory of U.S. Foreign Policy y Paul M. Sweezy, Leo Huberman (Monthly Review Pamphlet Series no. 16); Freedom under Capitalism and Socialism by Leo Huberman, Fritz Pappenheim Memorial Lecture (Monthly Review Pamphlet Series no. 26); Economic Aspects of U. S. Imperialism by Harry Magdoff (Monthly Review Pamphlet Series no. 27); How to Spread the Word by Leo Huberman, Originally Published December 1967 issue of Monthly Review, and: Notes on Left Propaganda by Leo Huberman, Originally Published September 1950 issue of Monthly Review; Revolution and Counterrevolution in the Dominican Republic: why the U.S. Invaded by Leo Huberman, Paul Sweezy Reprinted from September 1965 issue of Monthly Review; Cultural Revolution in China: a Socialist Analysis by Leo Huberman, Paul Sweezy Originally Published January 1967 issue of Monthly Review; Leo Huberman, October 17, 1903-November 9, 1968: a Memorial Service and Meeting of Friends, Community Church, New York City, December 2, 1968
    - Publications, Publishers, Presses, 1974-1982; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 114, Folder data_value_missing_826a255b87e930022b9d3727d2c70d43)